Tania Ostanina UX DESIGNER

A junior UX designer with a Master's Degree in Human-Computer Interaction Design (predicted distinction), backed by years of visual design experience.

With strong interpersonal skills in my arsenal, I am quickly able to drill down to the tiniest detail, collaborate and solve problems within fast-paced project environments.

DESIGN AND RESEARCH SKILLS

USER-CENTRED ITERATIVE DESIGN

Tate Halo (MSc portfolio project), dissertation

- Used the UCD process, with user testing after each design cycle.
- Created personas, storyboards and user journeys based on the results of user research, and ensured they were central to the design process.

PERSUASIVE TECHNOLOGY

Dissertation

- Focussed on the effective use of persuasive technology to influence climate change communication.
- The outcome will be a high fidelity mobile phone app prototype that motivates its users to talk about climate change.

INTERACTION DESIGN

Tate Halo

• Created an immersive interactive technology proposal for visitors to the Tate Modern, including wearable devices, an interactive digital screen and a large-scale interactive display. These were user tested with a positive result.

USER RESEARCH AND DATA ANALYSIS

Tate Halo, Homes > CO₂, dissertation

- Ensured that user research formed an integral part of the project process.
- Designed and ran questionnaires, interviews, desirability surveys.
- Carried out card sorting and tree testing online and in person.
- Coded research interview data using NVivo, synthesising the results into user requirements.

USABILITY TESTING

Swim22.diabetes.org.uk

- Designed and ran a usability test for a website of the charity Diabetes UK.
- Uncovered 23 usability problems, 4 of them serious.
- Wrote a report with recommendations for the charity.

PROTOTYPES AND WIREFRAMES

Multiple projects

Rapidly created paper and digital prototypes of varying degrees of fidelity.

INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE

Homes > CO₂

- Created a domain model, site map, user flow diagrams.
- Designed a faceted browse function to support searching of large databases.
- Supported discoverability and reduced 'pogo-sticking' by providing "You may also be interested in..." links on specific pages.

UI / VISUAL DESIGN

Multiple projects

- Designed the UI for several high-fidelity prototypes, as well as posters, booklets and graphics to support and enhance my HCID work.
- Years of experience representing ideas through sketching and digital tools.

INCLUSIVE DESIGN

evidentlycochrane.net

- Evaluated a website of Cochrane UK against WCAG accessibility guidelines.
- The results were used by the organisation to improve their website.





silvertrailux@gmail.com



+44(0) 7760 472456



MSc portfolio https://v.gd/silvertrailux



medium.com/@silvertrailux



linkedin.com/in/silvertrailux/

EDUCATION

City, University of London

MSc, Human-Computer Interaction Design (distinction expected 2020)

- Evaluating Interactive Systems
- Interaction Design
- Information Architecture
- Creativity in Design
- Inclusive Design
- Understanding User Interactions
- Data Visualisation
- MSc dissertation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Nicholas Hare Architects LLP

- Associate (2017-2019)
- Senior Architect (2014-2017)
- Architect (2010-2014)

TECHNICAL SKILLSET

Axure RP, Balsamiq, Figma, NVivo, Adobe Suite, Optimal Workshop, draw.io

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Communication:

- A proactive communicator, able to resolve tensions within the team and to justify my stance.
- Comfortable with organising and running meetings, having done so many times in my previous career (architecture) and during the MSc course.
- Working remotely with my team for the Creativity module (MSc HCID), I was able to complete a 'distinction' graded group coursework assignment, even under the pressure of the pandemic lockdown.

Collaboration and leadership:

 In my past architectural career, I was the project leader for several awardwinning, large-scale projects, coordinating the design output of both the in-house and the wider design teams, working closely with engineers and contractors.

Project management and organisation:

- Project managed the work of my team for the Creativity module (MSc HCID).
- In my past career, I planned and managed complex projects from conception to completion, organised the weekly workload of my team, meeting deadlines even in unforeseen circumstances.

Resilience and problem-solving:

• In my past career, I worked within a high-pressure, fast-paced environments to resolve complex issues quickly. My hands-on approach to problem-solving was praised by clients and design teams.

SPECIAL UX SKILLS AND PASSIONS

'Outside the box' creative thinking:

• I generated ideas for the HCID Creativity in Design module, not just by using standard ideation techniques, but by drawing inspiration from visiting the River Thames foreshore, studying online communities, and employing the techniques of 'Critical Fabulations.' I visually represented the project using a poetic storytelling narrative.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

UX blogging:

My UX blog *silvertrailux* has been featured in the online magazine *UX Collective* and on the front page of *Medium.com*.

Psychology:

I have an interest in the psychology of socially constructed silence, exploring these themes in my MSc dissertation.

Other hobbies:

Amateur artist and art historian, third culture kid, crazy cat lady.